

Mechanical Engineer & Python Developer JOSUE BANEGA

I'm mechanical engineer with solid Python programming skills. I have four year of experiences in the mining sector performing engineering analysis and product design using CAD/CAE tools and FEA/ CFD simulations. I seek to collaborate with a position like Modeling & Simulation Engineer.

Contact

- engineer@jbanega.com jban3ga@gmail.com josue.samuel.21@gmail.com
- Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela
- **** 0424-9713321
- www.jbanega.com
- n linkedin.com/in/jbanega
- github.com/jbanega

* Technologies

- Programming and data analysis: Python and MATLAB.
- 3D Modeling & Drawing: Autodesk Inventor and Solidworks.
- FEA and CFD Simulation: ANSYS, COMSOL Multiphysics and OpenFOAM.

Soft skills

- Adaptability.
- Problem-solving.
- Creativity.
- Teamwork.
- Self-motivated.

Work experience

Jan 2019 – Jan 2021

LUFH CONVEYOR BELT SYSTEMS

Technical Department / Development & Application Engineer

- In charge of technical drawing and design of 3D components using CAD software as Autodesk Inventor, ANSYS and COMSOL Multiphysics.
- Develop engineering analysis tools with user interface to automate tasks and provide guidance to internal/ external customers. Technologies used: Excel, VBA and Python.
- Write analyses and prepare presentations about the results and work performed. Tools used: Microsoft Office (Work, PowerPoint and Excel).

Aug 2017 – Dic 2018

CVG VENALUM

Technology and Development Department / Technology & Development Engineer Level I

- Perform hands-on concept development and prototyping to improve mechanical system using Autodesk Inventor, ANSYS and MATLAB.
- Running simulation based on finite element analyses (FEA) and computational fluid dynamic (CFD).
- Records and analyses data to reach design/ business decisions in plant.
- Interact with the experimental teams to develop and test new/ existing designs.

Education

2018 – 2019

MODELING AND SIMULATION SPECIALIZATION IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica Antonio José de Sucre (UNEXPO)

Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

2011 – 2016

BACHELOR DEGREE IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (SUMMA CUM LAUDE MENTION)

Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB)

Sartenejas, Venezuela

2002 – 2010

HIGH SCHOOL DEGREE IN SCIENCE

Unidad Educativa Colegio Los Próceres

Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

Papers & Conferences

11 Banega, J.; Moreno, N. (2018) <u>Aerodynamic Design of a VAWT suitable to wind profiles of Paraguaná by CFD</u>, Revista De La Facultad De Ingeniería, Universidad Central De Venezuela, 31(4), 83-92.

*Presented in The XIII International Congress of Numerical Methods in Engineering and Applied Sciences (CIMENICS 2016), Caracas, Venezuela, 11-13 July.

- engineer@jbanega.com jban3ga@gmail.com josue.samuel.21@gmail.com
- www.jbanega.com
- 🛅 🌘 /jbanega

Mechanical Engineer & Python Developer JOSUE BANEGA

Profile

Birth date: 26 June 1993. Nationality: Venezuela.

Teaching & Tutoring

[1] PhD. Caraballo, S.; Banega, J. (Dic 2018 – Jan 2019). Thermo-fluid-dynamic Simulation with COMSOL Multiphysics. Short course dictated as part of MODELING AND SIMULATION SPECIALIZATION IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING VII Promotion.

Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica Antonio José de Sucre (UNEXPO)

Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

[2] Bouzas, A. [Author]; Banega, J. [Industrial Tutor]; Andrade, J. [Academic Tutor] (2018) Modeling and Control of a Demolition Equipment to Clean Aluminium Melting Pots. Industrial training in CVG Venalum's Reduction Technology Division.

Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica Antonio José de Sucre (UNEXPO)

Barquisimeto, Venezuela

Languages

- Spanish: Advanced (Native).
- English: Intermedium -Advanced (B2).
- French: Basic (A1).

Certifications & Complementary courses

Jan 2021 GUI Development with Python and Tkinter

Udemy / Online

Jan 2021 Computational Thinking with Python

Platzi / Online

Aug 2020 English for Developers Course

Platzi / Online

Jul 2020 Basic Python Course

Platzi / Online

Mar 2020 Fundamentals in Polymer Processing

Instituto de Capacitación e Investigación del Plástico y del Caucho (ICIPC)

Barranquilla, Colombia

Feb 2020 – Sep 2020 Certificate of Proficiency English Level B2

Open English / Online

Oct 2019 – Nov 2019 Design Thinking

Instituto de Estudios Superiores de Administración (IESA) / Online

Nov 2017 Temperature Control with Fuzzy Logic

CVG Venalum / Puerto Ordaz. Venezuela

Sep 2015 ANSYS CFX – Introduction to V15.0

ALBATROS Ingeniería & Construcción C.A. / Caracas, Venezuela

■ Jan 2011 – Jun 2011 French Foundation Course

Lycée Saint Charles & American Field Service (AFS) / Marseille, France

Interests

- Python programming.
- App development.
- Machine learning.
- Computational mechanics (FEM/CFD).
- Vibration analysis.

Hobbies

- Reading.
- Travelling.
- 3D Modeling.
- Cinema.
- Airplane crafting.

Recognitions & Achievements

Oct 2016 Best Student Award, 2016 Edition

Decanato de Estudios Profesionales de la Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB)

*Recognition by excellent academic performance.